# ADAM GUTONSKI

1407 Glenmar Street Natrona Heights, Pennsylvania, 15065 (412)-584-3270 adamgutonski@protonmail.com

 $\hbox{\bf - Github\ Profile:}\ https://github.com/adamgutons$ 

- Web Portfolio: https://adamgutonski.com/

## **Summary**

I am an active front-end developer utilizing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. I have done back-end development with Java, the Java EE and Java Server Faces, and back-end database experience with PostgreSQL. I utilize Git and GitHub to manage my projects. My background in English from Allegheny College and prior work experience in sales has balanced out my technical experience and abilities.

#### **Technical Skills**

### **Programming/Languages:**

Python, Java, Java EE, Java Server Faces, SQL, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap

# **Databases Management:**

PgAdmin, PostgreSQL, SQL Server 2016

#### Other:

Linux (Ubuntu), Microsoft 10 and Office Products, spreadsheet knowledge from LibreOffice Calc, Apache Server (Digital Ocean), NetBeans, GitHub, Git

# **Related Experience**

### Technology Rediscovery - Turtle Creek Valley Code Enforcement

2017 - present:

- · Used Model-View-Controller design with Java Enterprise Edition, Java Server Faces for developing the web application
- Developed front-end pages using XHTML, HTML, CSS, along with Prime Faces for Java Server Faces
- · Coded back-end Java entities and backing-beans for data transfer to PostgreSQL database
- De-bugged program errors through call-stack interpretation

Languages/Tools Used: Java, Java Server Faces, Prime Faces, SQL, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Linux

# Main Squeeze Juice Web Host/Developer

2018 - present:

- Developed an e-commerce platform with Weebly webhosting to assist client with online sales during winter off-season
- Re-programmed portions of the HTML/CSS of custom Weebly host theme to deliver on client customization requests

Languages/Tools Used: Weebly web host, HTML, CSS, Linux

### Education

## Community College of Allegheny County - Pittsburgh, PA

Associate of Science, Computer Information Technology Program, Currently Enrolled, GPA: 3.86

Honors: Graduated with honors (GPA: 3.87), Dean's List 2017, 2018

**Program Focus:** Earned "A"s in all courses within the Computer Information Technology focus

Course Highlights: Intro to Java, Object-Oriented Programming: Java I, Python II, Databases,

Data Analytics, Statistics, Trigonometry

Allegheny College - Meadville, PA

Bachelor of Arts: English, Minor: Geology, 2013

## **Supplemental Experience**

SDG Consulting – Enrollment Advisor Citizens Bank – Senior Customer Support IPS Learning – Enrollment Advisor Tarentum Borough – Street Department Summer Help Jazz guitar, music theory Yoga/weight training 2018

2017

2013-2017

2010-2013